Alex Pain

alexjordanpain@gmail.com • +44 (0) 7548024315

A British Power BI Developer and System Administrator with 3 ½ of industry experience. Specialising in Windows environments as well as limited Linux experience. Experienced with on-site and hybrid infrastructures and a multitude of desktop and mobile operating systems (Windows XP - 11, Server 2003 - 2019, Debian, CentOS, SUSE, MacOS, iOS and Android). A passion for IT and developing my personal and technical skills. Hardworking, honest, and reliable individual with excellent customer service skills. Used to working closely with technical and non-technical staff. The ability to organise, prioritise, meet deadlines and adhere to service level agreements.

Employment

Middlesex Aerospace, Basingstoke, UK
Power Bi Developer - (September 2022 - Present)

- Designing, developing, and implementing Power BI solutions to meet business requirements. This involves creating data models, dashboards, reports, and interactive visualizations using Power BI Desktop and other related tools
- Analyzing and understanding complex data sets, including data from various sources such as SQL databases, Excel files, and APIs. Performing data cleansing, transformation, and modeling to ensure data accuracy and reliability
- Developing visually appealing and user-friendly reports and dashboards using Power BI features such as visualizations, drill-down capabilities, and interactive filters. Presenting data insights in a compelling and understandable manner to facilitate data-driven decision-making
- Configuring data refresh schedules and maintaining data consistency
- · Creating SQL views within SSMS

System Administrator - (January 2020 - Present)

- Maintaining and improving Windows environment to Microsoft best practices and resilience
- · Maintaining compliance to Cyber Essentials Plus certification requirements
- Technical authority for Microsoft 365 (Autopilot/Intune, Exchange, Teams) issues and user device security
- Improving current business processes through streamlining or automation solutions
- Providing all lines of support
- · Installation, configuration, and maintenance of operating systems and software
- Ensure systems are backed up, patched and secure e.g. Firewalls, VPNs, servers, content filter
- Creating and updating documentation
- Procurement of new hardware and upgrading of existing hardware

Both roles were worked simultaneously during the indicated dates as an opportunity to develop my Power Bi and SQL skills.

FROMM Packaging Ltd, Taplow, UK

Service Administrator - (August 2018 - December 2019)

- Ensuring product orders are placed, despatched and tracked to delivery / receipt to maintain quality & service
- · Addressing Customer concerns and additional enquiries
- · Providing technical sales advice
- Creating and maintaining rental contracts for Customers who wish to rent rather than purchase equipment
- · Preparation of quotations

Tech



Certifications

- Acquity Training Power Bi Introduction & Advanced
- Acquity DAX Introduction & Advanced
- Microsoft Technology Associate: Mobility and Device Fundamentals
- Microsoft Technology Associate: Networking Fundamentals
- BCS Level 3 Award in Cloud Processes
- BCS Level 3 Award in Coding and Logic
- BCS Level 3 Award in Business Processes

Education

Edgbarrow Secondary School 2008 - 2013

IT - BTEC Level 2 (Merit) Computing - GCSE (C) Maths - GCSE (C) English - GCSE (C)

Interests

- Electronics
- Reverse engineering
- Football
- Fishing
- Music

- · Creating monthly and annual rental invoices
- Responsible for planning a monthly service schedule for on-site engineers
- Ensuing all tasks and duties are underpinned by Company policies / Procedures + Compliance documentation

Projects

Cyber Essentials Plus

To become Cyber Essentials Plus compliant we had to build 3 new virtual Windows 2019 Servers (2 Domain Controllers, 1 File Server); prior to this Middlesex Aerospace had been running a Microfocus OES (previously Novell) file server and directory services for over 20 years. To support the new servers and provide additional capacity for the existing systems; we also added a new ISCSI switch and SAN with larger and faster disks; this was then configured and integrated with existing ESXi hosts.

AD Connect was installed onto the primary Domain Controller and AD users were imported from Microsoft 365. Whilst the existing production servers were running we built the AD structure and reviewed the OES file permissions and replicated them to their NTFS equivalent. Group policies for password requirements, printer and drive mappings, OneDrive known file move etc. were created.

Prior to migration; testing was carried out ensuring file permissions and group policies were functioning correctly.

ForensiT User Profile Wizard was used to join machines to the domain and migrate local profiles to domain profiles whilst keeping all data and settings.

A final file sync and comparison was made between the old Linux file server and new Windows file server on launch day and login to OES was disabled.

Multi-factor authentication was enabled for all users through conditional access policies within Azure Active Directory with a trusted site setup for our main office. As per CIS Benchmarks legacy authentication was disabled, SPF and DMARC records are published and DKIM is enabled.